hello and welcome to the 31st tutorial
on how to program your script 2. so in
this tutorial i'm going to show you
something called enable features and
something called show stats
so for this i created a new weapon
called disable
and i put client side and function
uncreated and this function on created
here's what we're going to put
i'm going to put enable
features
and to parenthesis semicolon
so this is going to do enable features
it's going to disable things such as
pressing p to pause
pressing q to look at your
weapons pressing m to see the map which
you can't do because i'm on gmap holding
r
um displaying nicknames displaying
hearts over people's heads displaying
chat the tab key that lets you chat it's
going to disable all that
and here is what's going to disable now
what these numbers are going to do which
i'll show in a second
is
what your these numbers are going to
specify what you want to disable or
enable
and feed all features is going to enable
everything
so let's say we want to disable the
pause button
well if you look now i press p it pauses
and no one can hit me well i don't want
that
let's go here and put enable features
and all features
because you want to enable everything
then we're going to put minus
minus 2
because if we look here
the pause button value is two
right okay we apply this
and now
i cannot press pause
anybody else if they do not have this
weapon they can do it so you could have
the weapon
get put on to anyone once they first
enter the server and then no one will be
able to pause
so that's pretty useful
now let's open this again
and let's disable something else let's
disable
um
disable the tab key so we can't chat
because we want to make our own chat
system
and we're going to put minus 0x
what number was that
80 no wasn't that
40.
so now you're disabling the pause and
the chat
do that
and now i can't
chat
and i can't pause or something like that
okay
so now
what we're going to do
is we're going to put something else
we're going to put
something else let's put minus
actually no let's say we want to disable
everything well we just take this all
and put a zero
now if i do that i can't press pause
can't
can't do anything that's
on this list
pretty much
now if we go here and put zero
or wouldn't that be zero we'll just put
one thing let's put a
let's put
four
four specifies
the q key which is weapon select
so we will we're gonna what this is
going to do is enable
the cue select but nothing else
so we hit that
we can't pause we can't chat we can't do
anything like that but we can press q
so that's enable features
let's just put
all features oh
all features
minus
and then p key 2.
so now we're going to put here is
show stats show stats this is pretty
similar to all features except it works
for a few different things show stats is
mainly for
icons these icons appear you can disable
all of them
you can disable right-clicking players
inventorying pcs you can actually
disable all the players so you can't see
anyone which is good if you want
something cinematic
so let's go here and i'm going to show
you the text document
here are all the values
over here on the left and here on the
right are what they do
so if we want to put all stats it's
going to enable everything let's do that
all stats now let's say we want to
disable the hearts and add our own heart
system which we'll add in another weapon
well i'm not going to do that but let's
say you wanted to do that
well i would put all stats so i wanted
any everything minus
what is it 0x20
oh x not that i don't know why i hit
that
or period
so if we look here
hearts is
0x20
so if we click that apply it the heart's
now gone
we can disable pretty much everything
this way
and let's see if we want to also disable
players
we'll put z minus
again minus 0x 400.
we hit that well it disables us too so
we don't want that
so let's have it disable the hearts
how about we also want to disable all
these icons
actually let's disable everything
except for these three things inventory
mpc's players and right-clicking
okay what we would do
is we would go here
put zero
or we don't have to put zero we could
just put anything here let's put um
what we want
zero x
200 plus
zero
x four hundred plus
zero x eight hundred
which are the values
for these three things that we want
okay
and
800. so hit that
it's disabled almost everything all our
icons here but the players are still
around
you can still right click people
and things like that so this concludes
this tutorial and now you understand how
you can disable default features and
create your own things
and if you combine this with let's say
disable
def movement
then you can create your own custom
movement your own custom health your own
custom anything you want
and
that's how you do it that conclusive
tutorial and i'll see you next time